



# Prem Bahadur Gurung's

# CURRICULUM –VITAE

IFMGA Mountain Guide







### NAMASTE

I was born on 16 December 1978 in Ilampokhari -8 LMJUNG near Mt. Manaslu region and brought up in the beautiful hilly region of Nepal. The snow-covered peaks fascinated me from early childhood. As I grew up, the urge to experience the mountains from close quarters became my dream. To take my ambition a step ahead, I enrolled in national and international training in mountaineering. I am now a certified Diploma in Mountain Guide (IFMGA/UIAGM) and instructor and I bring twenty-four years of experience in mountaineering and trekking skills. I have vast experience organizing and leading treks and mountaineering expeditions in the Himalayas and climbing experience in France, Italy and Swiss Alps. I participated in more than 28 expeditions above 6,000m including Mount Everest (2007 and 2009), (Amadablam 2008/2010/2011), Mt. Kanchenjunga (2012) and Manaslu (2011) as an expedition leaders and Mountain guide.

I am always ready to assist you to organize peak climbing, Trekking, Mountaineering expeditions, tours and climbing training to scale the mountains of Nepal, the Alps, India & Tibet. I'll take care of all the details once we know your needs. Our goal is to provide you with the highest level of service and safety, whether your goal is to summit Everest or master a 6,000m, 7,000m, or 8,000m peak.

## **CURRICULUM –VITAE**

Personal Information

Name : **PREM BAHADUR GURUNG** 

Date of Birth : 16/12/1978

Father's Name : Purna Bahadur Gurung

Nationality : Nepali Gender : Male

Education : Diploma in Mountain Guide

Religion : BON Marital status : Married

Language : Nepali, English & Hindi

Contact Information

Permanent Address:

ElamPokhari-8, Lamjung, Gandaki, Nepal

Temporary Address: lekhnath-30, pokhara, Kaski

Cell: +977-9856008848

Facebook- https://www.facebook.com/peak | 5/

Instagram:- <a href="https://www.instagram.com/premguide/">https://www.instagram.com/premguide/</a>

E-mail: 8848prem@gmail.com

Teaching Experience: from 2004 till now

Visited country: : France, Italy, Swiss, Norway, Sweden, Finland, Greece, Netherland, German, Hong Kong, Japan, Taiwan, South Korea, Thailand, Singapore, Malaysia, China, India

# Affiliated Association

- ✓ Member & Instructor (NMIA)
- ✓ Instructor & member (NMA)
- ✓ Instructor & member (NNMGA)
- ✓ Nepal Mountain Academy (Instructor)
- ✓ IFMGA / UIAA / UAAA / IFSC
- ✓ Gandaki Alpine Club (Founder member)

#### Sport Background

- ✓ Football (local club)
- √ Volleyball (from School)
- ✓ Ski
- ✓ Swimming
- ✓ Sport climbing

# Canyoning exploring in Nepal-2005

- ✓ Bulbule Khola, lamjung
- √ Jaget khola, lamjung
- ✓ Chamje khola, lamjung
- ✓ Kabindra Khola, lamjung
- ✓ Rindu khola, lamjung
- √ 13 kilo Kakani, kathmandu

#### Teaching Experience

- ✓ Instructor in Basic and advance mountaineering 2004 to 2018
- Basic and Advance Mountaineering training as Chief Instructor
- ✓ basic and advance rock climbing training in France 2005 to 2008 from FFCAM
- ✓ Instructor -alpine mountaineering course in France 2007 from FFCAM
- ✓ Instructor in Trekking Guide course 2004-2010 (NATHM).
- ✓ Instructor in 2006 / 2010 for liaison officer Equipment familiarization (NATHM)
- ✓ Instructor in basic, level-1 and high mountain rescue training 2006 to 2017
- ✓ Mountain Navigation Course (2004-till now)
- ✓ Instructor and Judge –wall climbing competition in Pasang lamu foundation (2007-Apirl)
- ✓ Sport climbing trainer and climbing route setter
- ✓ Senior Mountain guide course as guide and instructor 2012
- ✓ IFSC open National sport climbing competition Nepal As official technical coordinator 2012
- √ Thailand teaching Rock guide and mountaineering leader in May 2013
- √ Thailand- teaching mountain rescue training 2018
- ✓ Taiwan- teaching mountain rescue training 2016
- Nepal Mountain Academy trekking guide course 2017 to 2022
- Instructor in aspirant guide and full mountain guide training NNMGA 2010,2011,2012, 2014, 2016
- ✓ HSC (+2) mountaineering education in Taplejung 2022, from Nepal mountain academy
- ✓ BMC and MMC Nepal mountain academy





#### **Training**

- ✓ Trekking guide Training (NATHM),
- √ Navigation Course (NMIA)
- ✓ Basic Mountaineering Training (NMA)
- ✓ Advance Mountaineering Training (NMA),
- ✓ First Aid and CPR (NMIA, Alliance Françoise, ENSA)
- Canyoning Guide Training (By French instructor)
   2005 in winter,
- ✓ Mountain Rescue training (NMA, NMIA),
- Mountaineering Instructor Course 2005 from School of National Ski and Alpinism Under Ministry of sport France (ENSA),
- ✓ Training of Trainers (ToT) Fédération Française des clubs alpins et de montagne (FFCAM) France 2008
- ✓ Trad big wall climbing course from collegio regionale
  Guide alpine lombardia, Italy
- Himalaya Rescue training (EV-K2-CNR, RONAST, NMA, NTB, Lombardy region Alpine Guides Italy)
- ✓ Heli long line rescue training in ITALY 2006
- High Mountain Rescue training (NMIA, GENDAMERIA-CNISAG France, NMA)
- ✓ ASPIRANT Guide course 2007-jan-feb (NNMGA)
- ✓ ASPIRANT Guide course 2008-finel (NNMGA)
- ✓ Instructor refreshment training from Yves Pollet Villard Foundation (YPVF) in France July Sep 2008
- ✓ Full Mountain Guide Course(Nepal National Mountain Guide Association (NNMGA) Supervision under UIAGM/IFMGA-5<sup>th</sup> to 18 Jan 2009
- WRT- Whitewater rescue training technician course- RESUCE 3 INTERNATIONAL -7 to 9 July 2010
- ✓ Ski Training in France 2010 to 2012 UCPA and ENSA
- ✓ IFSC route setting and Judge training NMA/IFSC
- ✓ Ski refreshment course Swiss and France NNMGA / Nepal mountain Academy / ENSA 2017

#### Trekking Experience

Everest, Langtang, Kanchenjunga, Makalu, Annapurna, Manaslu, Upper Mustang, Dhaulagiri, RARA Lake, Dolpo

France, Taiwan, India (Ladahk and Kashmir)

#### Climbing Experience in Nepal

- ✓ Pisang peak (Aanapurna-2002 /2003-2009),
- ✓ Nawal peak(Aanapurna-2003),
- Yala peak/Yala chang(Langtang-2004/2006 2007-2008-2009-2010),
- ✓ Singha-Chuli peak(Aanapurna B.C.-2003-2004-2005)
- ✓ Chulu west- 2009-2010,
- ✓ Mera peak(Everest-2005to2010),
- ✓ Island peak(Everest-2005 to 2017),
- ✓ Chulu-east(Aanapurna-2006- 2009),
- Aamadablam ( 2005 and 2008)
- ✓ Tent peak (Aanapurna B.C-2006-2009),
- Dhampus peak (Daulagiri-elavation camp- 6054m.-2006).
- Everest EXP.-2007 Oct (camp-4-south col) and 2009 (8100m)
- ✓ Winter ice climbing basic and advance training (feb 02-12, in rolwalling area) and Manang 2017 humde
- ✓ Dhaulagiri- camp 2(May 7-14,2008) rescue proposed
- √ Ama Dablam C2 2008 and C3 2001 I Autumn
- ✓ Labuche peak (2008 to 2017)
- ✓ Manaslu C3 /2011/ Spring
- ✓ Kanchenjunga 8586- 8300m/Spring/2012
- ✓ Norbu peak 5800m rolwaling north route, new route explore 2012
- ✓ Khang Tsar-Tse 5820m Manang 2017 new route explore

#### Search and Rescue (SAR) experience

- ✓ Kangkaru (2005-2006)
- ✓ Labuche (2005)
- ✓ Rescue Team member Taplejung Ghunsa helicopter clash 23 SEP 2006
- ✓ Amadablam 2008 Autumn
- ✓ Dhaulagiri 2008 in May, search
- ✓ Mountain rescue work with NMA and HRA 2005 to 2009

#### **New Route setting on Rock climbing in NEPAL:**

S.N.	Route Name	Height	Grade	Location
I	Hungry eye route	13 m.	5c-6a,	Raniban, Balaju
2	Padam step	15 m.	6a,	Hattibaan (sallaghari)
3	Dec. I <sup>st</sup>	15 m.	6a,	Hattibaan, Pharping
4	Iman ko samjhanama	50 m.	6a-6a+-6b,	Bimalnagar Tanahun
5	Pheri parkyo	15 m.	6b+	Hattibaan, Pharping
6	Training	10 m.	6a	Bimalnager Tanahun
7	Cheeparo	10 m.	6c	Bimalnager Tanahun
8	Odar	12 m.	6a+	Bimalnager Tanahun
9	Carck jasto	12 m.	6a	Bimalnager Tanahun
10	Bachaa	06 m.	5c	Bimalnager Tanahun
П	Christmas	15 m.	6b+	Bimalnager Tanahun
12	Samzeta	14 m.	6a	Hattiban, Pharping
13	Lover Boys	16 m.	6a,6b	Bimal nager Tanahun
14	Project route	22 m.	N/A	Brathang, Manang
15	Nano Sloper	24 m.	6b	Koto, Manang





	16	Watch out	16 m.	<b>6</b> a	Brathang, Manang
	17	Black power	18 m.	7a	Brathang, Manang
	18	Daniel frication	28 m.	<b>6</b> c	Koto, Manang
Ī	19	Phycho "saiko"	18 m.	<b>6</b> a	Brathang, Manang
Ī	20	Muskan	45 m.	<b>6</b> b	Bimalnagr, Tanahun

# Winter ice climbing explore and research in NEPAL 2012 to 2017

S.N.	Area	Route	Height	Grade	Location
I	Humde	4 route	400 meter max	WI-3 to WI-5	Manang, Annapurna
2	Gangapurna	2 route	150 meter max	WI-3 to WI-5	Manang, Annapurna
3	Annapurna Base camp	2 route	250 meter max	WI-3 to WI-5	Annapurna base camp
4	Na- village	7 route	150 meter max	WI-3 to WI-5	Rolwaling dolakha

# Climbing in Europe (2005-2007-2008-2010-2013-2015-2016)

Note-		
•	NMIA	Nepal mountaineering instructors association
•	NNMGA	Nepal National mountain guide association
•	NMA	Nepal Mountain Academy
•	HRA	Himalayan Rescue Association
•	NATHM	Nepal academy of tourism hotel management
•	NMA	Nepal mountaineering association
•	RONAST	Royal Nepal Academy of Science and Technology
•	NTB	Nepal tourism Board
•	ENSA	School of National Ski and Alpinism Under Ministry of sport France
	IFMGA	International Federation of Mountain Guide Association
	UIAGM	Union Internationale des Associations de Guides de Montagnes
	IFSC	International federation of sport climbing
•	UIAA	Union of international Alpine Association
	UAAA	Union of Asia Alpine Association
	YPVF	Yves Pollet Villard Foundation
•	FFCAM	Fédération Française des clubs alpins et de montagne
•	UCPA	The Union nationale des centres sportifs de plein air